Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
隆冬嚴寒  漫天雨雪
Born of cold and winter air and mountain rain combining
冰封之力  無情又無私
This icy force both foul and fair
辛勤開墾這冰雪之心
Has a frozen heart worth mining
切開冰冷清澈的結晶
So cut through the heart, cold and clear
對這冰雪又愛又恨
Strike for love and strike for fear
冰封美景
See the beauty sharp and sheer
割開堅冰
Split the ice apart
打碎冰雪之心
And break the frozen heart
嘿  呦  留神腳下  別逞強
Hup! Ho! Watch your step! Let it go
美麗又強大
Beautiful! Powerful
危險又冷酷
Dangerous! Cold
冰雪是不受約束的魔法
Ice has a magic can't be controlled
勝過一人  勝過十人
Stronger than one, stronger than ten
勝過成百上千人
Stronger than a hundred men
隆冬嚴寒  漫天雨雪
Born of cold and winter air and mountain rain combining
冰封之力  無情又無私
This icy force both foul and fair
辛勤開墾這冰雪之心
Has a frozen heart worth mining
切開冰冷清澈的結晶
Cut through the heart, cold and clear
對這冰雪又愛又恨
Strike for love and strike for fear
美麗和危險為伴
There's beauty and there's danger here
割開堅冰
Split the ice apart
小心冰雪之心
Beware the frozen heart
跟上  斯溫
Come on, Sven!
喂  艾爾莎
Elsa. Psst!
艾爾莎
Elsa!
醒醒  醒醒  快醒醒
Wake up. Wake up. Wake up.
安娜  快回去睡覺吧
Anna, go back to sleep.
我就是睡不著  天上有光  我就睡不著
I just can't. The sky's awake, so I'm awake,
所以起來玩吧
so we have to play.
你自己去玩吧
Go play by yourself.
快來陪我堆雪人嘛
Do you want to build a snowman?
快來  快來  快來  快來
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
快用魔法  快用魔法
Do the magic! Do the magic!
準備好了嗎
Ready?
太神奇了
This is amazing!
看這個
Watch this!
你好  我叫奧洛夫  我喜歡熱情的擁抱
Hi, I'm Olaf and I like warm hugs.
我喜歡你  奧洛夫
I love you, Olaf.
-等等  -接住我  -接住你了
- Hang on. - Catch me! - Gotcha!
-再來一次  -等等
- Again! - Wait!
慢點兒
Slow down!
安娜
Anna!
Anna?
媽媽  爸爸
Mama! Papa!
你沒事的  安娜  我會保護你的
You're okay, Anna. I got you.
艾爾莎  你幹了什麼  太過分了
Elsa, what have you done? This is getting out of hand!
這是個意外  我很抱歉  安娜
It was an accident. I'm sorry, Anna.
-她像冰一樣冷  -我知道該去哪兒
- She's ice cold. - I know where we have to go.
冰
Ice?
再快點  斯溫
Faster, Sven!
斯溫
Sven!
請幫幫我
Please... Help!
我女兒她
My daughter!
是國王
He is the King!
地精
Trolls...?
安靜  我正聽著呢
Shush. I'm trying to listen.
小可愛們  我要把你們都留下
Cuties. I'm gonna keep you.
國王陛下
Your Majesty!
是生來就有還是中了惡咒
Born with the powers or cursed?
生來就有  而且法力越來越強了
Born. And they're getting stronger.
幸好傷到的不是她的心
You are lucky it wasn't her heart.
心不容易恢復
The heart is not so easily changed,
頭卻不難治好
but the head can be persuaded.
請你盡力
Do what you must.
我建議抹去所有和魔法有關的東西
I recommend we remove all magic,
為了保險  有魔法的記憶都不要留
even memories of magic to be safe...
但是別擔心  快樂的記憶還在
But don't worry, I'll leave the fun.
她會沒事的
She will be okay.
她不會記得我的魔法嗎
But she won't remember I have powers?
-安全起見  -聽我說  艾爾莎
- It's for the best. - Listen to me, Elsa,
你的魔法只會日漸增強
your power will only grow.
雖然是美好的
There is beauty in it...
但也有危險
but also great danger.
你必須學會控制
You must learn to control it.
恐懼是你的敵人
Fear will be your enemy.
不  我們會保護他  她肯定能學會控制
No. We'll protect her. She can learn to control it. I'm sure.
不過現在
Until then,
還是關上城門  遣散僕從
we'll lock the gates. We'll reduce the staff.
儘量減少她與別人的接觸
We will limit her contact with people
防止別人知道她的魔法
and keep her powers hidden from everyone...
包括安娜
including Anna.
艾爾莎
Elsa?
快來陪我堆雪人嘛
Do you want to build a snowman
我們一起出去玩吧
Come on let's go and play
我再也沒見到你  快出來呀
I never see you anymore. Come out the door
你好像離開我了
It's like you've gone away
我們曾是好夥伴
We used to be best buddies
現在你卻不理我  快告訴我為什麼
And now we're not. I wish you would tell me why
快來陪我堆雪人嘛
Do you want to build a snowman
不堆雪人也可以呀
It doesn't have to be a snowman
走吧  安娜
Go away, Anna.
好吧  再見
Okay bye
戴著手套會有幫助  瞧
The gloves will help. See...
-封閉起來  -不要去感受
- Conceal it. - Don't feel it.
別讓人看清
Don't let it show.
快來陪我堆雪人嘛
Do you want to build a snowman
或是騎車繞大廳跑
Or ride our bike around the hall
好久沒人陪我玩
I think some company is overdue
我都只能對畫唱歌了
I've started talking to the pictures on the walls
撐住  貞德
Hang in there, Joan.
房間這麼空  內心好孤單
It gets a little lonely all these empty rooms
看時光滴答流逝
Just watching the hours tick by
我很害怕  魔法越來越強了
I'm scared. It's getting stronger.
害怕只會越來越糟
Getting upset only makes it worse.
冷靜下來
Calm down.
不  別碰我  求你了  我不想傷害你
No. Don't touch me. Please. I don't want to hurt you.
我們兩周後見
See you in two weeks.
-你們一定要走嗎  -你會沒事的  艾爾莎
- Do you have to go? - You'll be fine, Elsa.
艾爾莎
Elsa?
求你了  我知道你在裡面
Please, I know you're in there
人們都在打聽你的下落
People are asking where you've been
他們說要勇敢  我也在努力
They say have courage and I'm trying to
我就在門外  讓我進來吧
I'm right out here for you. Just let me in
現在只剩你我
We only have each other
我們彼此相依
It's just you and me
我們究竟該怎麼辦
What are we gonna do
快來陪我堆雪人嘛
Do you want to build a snowman
三   年   後
-歡迎來到阿倫黛爾  -謝謝您  先生
- Welcome to Arendelle! - Merci, monsieur!
請小心腳下  城門馬上就會開啟
Watch your Steps please. The gates will opening Soon.
為什麼我非得穿這個
Why do I have to wear this?
因為女王已經成年
Because the Queen has come of age.
今天是加冕日
It's Coronation Day!
那又不是我的錯
That's not my fault.
-你想要什麼  斯溫  -給我個點心
- What do you want, Sven? - Give me a snack!
-那暗號是什麼  -請給我
- What's the magic word? - Please!
喂喂喂  一人一半
A..A... a... a! Share!
今天城門居然開啟了
I can't believe they're finally opening up the gates!
而且是開一整天
And for a whole day!
快點兒  珀西
Faster, Persi!
阿倫黛爾  我最神秘的交易夥伴
Ah, Arendelle, our most mysterious trade partner.
開啟了城門等著我探尋
Open those gates so I may unlock your secrets
榨取財富
and exploit your riches.
我是不是說得太大聲了
Did I just say that out loud?
我已經等不及想看看
Oh, me sore eyes can't wait to
女王陛下和公主殿下了
see the Queen and the Princess.
她們一定非常可愛
I bet they're absolutely lovely.
肯定是美麗動人
I bet they are beautiful.
安娜公主
Princess Anna...?
什麼事
Huh? Yeah?
-抱歉打擾  但是殿下  -不不不  沒有
- Sorry to wake you, ma'am but... - No, no, no. You didn't.
我已經起床很久了
I've been up for hours.
誰啊
Who is it?
還是我  殿下  城門馬上就要開啟
It's still me, ma'am. The gates will open soon.
-該做準備了  -當然
- Time to get ready. - Of course!
準備什麼
Ready for what?
您姐姐的加冕儀式  殿下
Your sister's coronation, ma'am.
姐姐的加冕儀式
My sister's cor-neration...
今天是加冕日
It's coronation day!
窗戶和大門都已開啟
The window is open! So's that door
好久沒有這樣過
I didn't know they did that anymore
誰知道我們有八千個沙拉碟呢
Who knew we owned 8000 salad plates
我在這空蕩的大廳漫步多年
For years I have roamed these empty halls
沒有舞會  要舞廳有什麼用
Why have a ballroom with no balls
終於  城門就要開啟了
Finally, they're opening up the gates
都是有血有肉的人
There'll be actual, real-life people
這感覺好奇怪
It'll be totally strange
可我早已準備好了
But wow am I so ready for this change
因為好久以來
'Cause for the first time in forever
會有音樂  伴著燈光
There'll be music, there'll be light
因為好久以來
For the first time in forever
我將徹夜翩然起舞
I'll be dancing through the night
我不知道是興奮還是得意
Don't know if I'm elated or gassy
但總之也差不多
But I'm somewhere in that zone
因為好久以來
'Cause for the first time in forever
我將不再孤單  我等不及見到大家
I won't be alone. I can't wait to meet everyone...
如果遇到真命天子呢
What if I meet "The one"?
今晚  想像自己禮服加身
Tonight, imagine me gown and all
迷人地斜倚著牆
Fetchingly draped against the wall
好一幅精緻優雅的畫面
The picture of sophisticated Grace
驀然回首  看到我的他
I suddenly see him standing there
素未謀面  面容俊朗
a beautiful stranger tall and fair
我只想嘴裡塞滿巧克力
I wanna stuff some chocolate in my face
但我們徹夜暢談歡笑
But then we laugh and talk all evening
說起來也奇怪
Which is totally bizarre
和以前的生活截然不同
Nothing like the life I've led so far
好久好久以來
For the first time in forever
生活中充滿了魔法和歡樂
There'll be magic, there'll be fun
好久好久以來
For the first time in forever
我會受人矚目
I could be noticed by someone
我知道這是瘋言瘋語
And I know it is totally crazy
想像自己能找到真愛
To dream I'd find romance
但這是好久以來
But for the first time in forever
至少我有了機會
At least I've got a chance
掩藏好自己  不許人靠近
Don't let them in. Don't let them see
乖乖聽話  別讓大家擔心
Be the good girl You always have to be
把真心封閉
Conceal. Don't feel.
演好這齣戲
Put on a show.
走錯一步  就會人盡皆知
Make one wrong move and everyone will know
只是為了今天
But it's only for today
It's only for today
等待使人心焦
It's agony to wait
通知守衛打開  城門
Tell the guards to open up the gate
打開城門
The gate
這是好久以來
For the first time in forever
我將獲得夢想的一切
I'm getting what I'm dreaming of.
乖乖聽話  別讓大家擔心
Be the good girl you always have to be.
改變我生活的機會
A chance to change my only world.
把真心封閉
Conceal.
一個獲得真愛的機會
A chance to find true love
把真心封閉  不讓人看清
Conceal. Don't feel, Don't let them know
我知道明天一切將會結束
I know it all ends tomorrow
所以必須抓住今天
So it has to be today
因為這是好久以來
'Cause for the first time in forever
好久以來
For the first time in forever
什麼都無法阻止我
Nothing's in my way
我很抱歉  你受傷了嗎
I'm so sorry. Are you hurt?
你好
Hey!
-對  不  我沒事  -真的嗎
- I-ya, no. No. I'm okay. - Are you sure?
沒錯  是我走路不小心
Yeah, I just wasn't looking where I was going.
-但是我真的沒事  -謝天謝地
- But I'm great, actually. - Oh, thank goodness.
我是南部群島的漢斯王子
Prince Hans of the Southern Isles.
-我是阿倫黛爾的公主  -公主
- Princess Anna of Arendelle. - Princess...?
公主殿下
My Lady.
你好啊
Hi... again.
老天
Oh boy.
真尷尬  不是說你
Ha. This is awkward. Not you're awkward,
但是我們  是我很尷尬
but just because we're...I'm awkward.
你好帥  我說啥了
You're gorgeous. Wait, what?
我想為騎馬撞到阿倫黛爾的公主殿下
I'd like to formally apologize for
以及之後發生的種種
hitting the Princess of Arendelle with my horse...
向你正式道歉
and for every moment after.
不  沒關係  我並不是那位公主
No. No-no. It's fine. I'm not THAT Princess.
我是說  要是你撞到我姐姐艾爾莎  那可就
I mean, if you'd hit my sister Elsa, that would be...
不好說了
'cuz, you know...
你好
Hello.
但是  幸好  只是我而已
But, lucky you, it's-it's just me.
只是你
Just you?
鳴鐘了  是加冕儀式
The bells. The coronation.
我  我
I... I...
我要走了  我必須得走了
I better go. I have to...I better go.
再見
Bye!
陛下  手套
Your Majesty, The gloves.
在此聖地  為您加冕
Sem hon heldr inum helgum eignum ok
至尊無上  統禦全境
krýnd í þessum helga stað ek té fram fyrir yðr
阿倫黛爾的女王艾爾莎
Queen Elsa of Arendelle.
有請阿倫黛爾的女王艾爾莎
有請阿倫黛爾的公主安娜
Princess Anna of Arendelle!
站這兒  你確定  我覺得不該  好吧
Here? Are you sure? I do not think I suppose to...Okay.
你好
Hi.
是在和我說話嗎  你好
Hi me...? Oh. Um. Hi.
-你看上去很美  -謝謝
- You look beautiful... -Thank you.
你看上去更圓  不是圓
You look beautifuller. I mean, not fuller.
你一點都不圓  我是說更美
You don't look fuller, but more beautiful.
謝謝
Thank you.
宴會就是這個樣子的嗎
So, this is what a party looks like?
比我想像中的要溫馨得多
It's warmer than I thought.
那奇妙的香味是什麼
And what is that amazing smell?
是巧克力
Chocolate.
女王陛下  這是猥瑣屯公爵
Your Majesty. The Duke of Weaseltown.
是韋瑟頓  韋瑟頓公爵
Weselton. The Duke of Weselton..
陛下
Your Majesty,
作為您最親密的交易夥伴
as your closest partner in trade,
我應該請您跳
it seems only fitting that I offer you
加冕後的第一支舞
your first dance as Queen.
謝謝  可是我不跳舞
Thank you. Only I don't dance.
但我妹妹可以
But my sister does.
-你真幸運  -我想還是
- Lucky you...- Oh, I don't think...
如果你暈過去  告訴我  我會接住你
If you swoon, let me know, I'll catch you.
抱歉
Sorry.
就像只機敏的孔雀
Like an agile peacock...
說起來  城門能開啟真是太好了
Speaking of, so great to have the gates open.
為什麼之前都要關閉呢
Why did they shut them in the first place?
你知道原因嗎
Do you know the reason? Hmm?
我不知道
No. No...
好吧  撐住
Oh, all right. Hang on.
我的外號"小北斗星"可不是浪得虛名
They don't call me "The little dipper" for nothing.
就像一隻猴面雞身的動物  我能飛
Like a chicken...with the face of a monkey... I fly.
準備好再跳一輪的時候請告訴我  殿下
Let me know when you're ready for another round, My Lady.
他真是精力充沛
Well, he was sprightly.
尤其他還穿著高跟鞋
Especially for a man in heels.
-你還好嗎  -我從來沒這麼開心過
- Are you okay? - I've never been better.
感覺太棒了
This is so nice.
我希望以後都能像今天這樣
I wish it could be like this all the time.
我也是
Me too...
但是不行
But it can't.
-為什麼  -就是不行
- Why not? If... - It just can't.
那我先走了
Excuse me for a minute.
-幸虧我抓住你了  -漢斯
- Glad I caught you. - Hans!
我一般都是一個人亂跑  抱歉
I often had the whole parlor to myself to slide... Oops. Sorry.
你的身材也很不錯
Your physique helps, I'm sure too.
-這是什麼  -我生來就有這個
- What's this? - I was born with it,
雖然夢裡是被地精親吻過才有的
Although I dreamt I was kissed by a troll.
我很喜歡
I like it.
對  所有的一切  你懂的
Yeah, The whole thing! You got it.
等等  你到底有多少個兄弟
Okay wait, wait. So you have how many brothers?
十二個哥哥
Twelve older brothers.
有兩年他們中的三個
Three of them pretended I was invisible...
完全忽視我的存在
literally... for two years.
-太糟糕了  -哥哥們都這樣
- That's horrible. - It's what brothers do.
姐姐也是
And sisters.
小時候艾爾莎和我非常親密
Elsa and I were really close when we were little.
但後來有一天  她也把我拒之門外
But then, one day she just shut me out, and...
我從來不知道原因
And I never knew why.
我永遠不會將你拒之門外
I would never shut you out.
我能說點瘋話嗎
Okay, can I just say something crazy?
我喜歡聽瘋話
I love crazy.
我的生活不過是面前的一扇又一扇門
All my life has been a series of doors in my face
但是突然之間  我撞見了你
And then suddenly I bump into you
我也這麼想  因為
I was thinking the same thing, because like
我窮盡一生只為尋找自我
I've been searching my whole life to find my own place
也許因為這是派對
And maybe it's the party talking
或是巧克力火鍋
Or the chocolate fondue
但和你在一起
But with you
我找到了自我
I found my place
看到你的臉
I see your face
這感覺從未有過
And it's nothing like I've ever known before
愛是一扇相互敞開的心門
Love is an open... door
Love is an open... door...door
愛是一扇相互敞開的心門
Love is an open... door
和你在一起  和你在一起
With you! With you
愛是一扇相互敞開的心門
Love is an open door
-這太瘋狂了  -什麼
- I mean it's crazy. - What?
-我們吃完了對方的  -三明治
- We finish each other's... - Sandwiches!
我正想說這個
That's what I was gonna say
我從未遇到過和我如此默契的人
I've never met someone who thinks so much like me
拉鉤  再拉鉤
Jinx... jinx again.
我們心意相通  只有一個原因
Our mental synchronization can have but one explanation
你和我是命中註定
You and I were just meant to be
說再見
Say goodbye
對過去的痛苦
To the pain of the past
我們無需再那樣活
We don't have to feel it anymore
愛若開啟的門
Love is an open... door
Love is an open door
生命有你更精彩
Life can be so much more...with you... with you
愛若開啟的門
Love is an open... door
我能說句瘋狂的話嗎
Can I say something crazy...?
你願意嫁給我嗎
Will you marry me?
我能說句更瘋狂的話嗎
Can I just say something even crazier?
我願意
Yes.
借過  不好意思  能借過一下嗎
Oops! Pardon. Sorry. Can we just get around you there?
謝謝  她在那裡
Thank you. Oh, there she is.
艾爾莎  我是說  女王陛下
Elsa! I mean... Queen...
還是我  請允許我介紹
Me again. May I present,
南部群島的漢斯王子
Prince Hans of the Southern Isles.
女王陛下
Your Majesty.
我們希望得到您的祝福
We would like...your blessing...
祝福我們結婚
of... our marriage!
-結婚  -是的
- Marriage...? - Yes!
抱歉  我沒弄明白
I'm sorry, I'm confused.
我們還沒有討論細節
Well, We haven't worked out all the details ourselves.
我們會花幾天時間計畫婚禮
We'll need a few days to plan the ceremony.
當然婚禮上會有湯羹
Of course we'll have soup,
烤肉  冰淇淩  還有...
roast, and ice cream and then...
等等  我們要住在這裡嗎
Wait. Would we live here?
-這裡  -當然了
- Here? - Absolutely!
安娜
Anna...
我們可以邀請你12個哥哥過來一起住
Oh, we can invite all twelve of your brothers to stay with us...
什麼  等等  不  不
What? No, no, no, no, no.
我們有的是房間  也許他們...
Of course we have the room. I don't know. Some of them must...
等等  停一停
Wait. Slow down.
誰的哥哥都不會住在這裡
No one's brothers are staying here.
誰都不會結婚
No one is getting married.
你說什麼
Wait, what?
能私下跟你聊幾句嗎
May I talk to you, please. Alone.
不  你要說什麼
No. Whatever you have to say, you...
可以當著我倆的面說
you can say to both of us.
好吧  你不能嫁給一個剛認識的人
Fine. You can't marry a man you just met.
當然可以  我們是真愛
You Can if it's true love.
你對真愛瞭解多少
Anna, what do you know about true love?
起碼比你瞭解  你只知道把人拒之門外
More than you. All you know is how to shut people out.
你們想得到我的祝福  我回答是不
You asked for my blessing, but my answer is no.
恕我失陪
Now, excuse me.
女王陛下  容我...
Your Majesty, if I may ease your...
不用說了  請你離開
No, you may not. And I-I think you should go.
宴會結束了  關上大門
The party is over. Close the gates.
遵命  女王陛下
Yes, Your Majesty.
什麼  艾爾莎  不要  等等
What? Elsa, no. No, wait!
把手套還給我
Give me my glove!
艾爾莎  求求你  我無法再這樣生活了
Elsa, please. Please. I can't live like this anymore.
那就離開
Then leave.
我到底怎麼惹到你了
What did I ever do to you?!
夠了  安娜
Enough, Anna.
為什麼  你為什麼把我拒之門外
No. Why? Why do you shut me out?!
為什麼把全世界拒之門外
Why do you shut the world out?!
你到底害怕什麼
What are you so afraid of?!
我說了  夠了
I said, enough!
妖術  我就知道
Sorcery. I knew there was
這裡有不可告人的秘密
something dubious going on here.
艾爾莎
Elsa...?
她在那裡
There she is.
女王陛下  女王萬歲
Your Majesty! Long live the Queen! Queen Elsa...
與我們喝一杯吧
Come drink with us.
艾爾莎女王
Queen Elsa.
女王陛下  你沒事吧
Your Majesty? Are you all right?
她在那裡  攔住她
There she is! Stop her!
拜託  別靠近我
Please, just stay away from me.
離我遠點
Stay away!
怪物  怪物
Monster... Monster!
艾爾莎
Elsa!
Elsa...
等等  求你
Wait, Please!
艾爾莎  停下
Elsa, Stop!
-安娜  -不要走
- Anna! - No.
海灣
The Fjord.
雪
Snow?
是雪
Yes, snow!
-你還好嗎  -不好
- Are you all right? - No.
-你之前知道嗎  -不知道
- Did you know? - No.
看  下雪了  下雪了
Look! It's snowing! It's snowing!
這個地方被女王詛咒了
The Queen has cursed this land!
我們一定要阻止她
She must be stopped!
-你們得把她抓回來  -等等  不要
- You have to go after her...- Wait, no!
你  你也會妖術嗎
You! Is there sorcery in you, too?
你也是怪物嗎
Are you a monster, too?
不  不  我是很普通的人
No. No. I'm completely ordinary.
沒錯  她很普通
That's right she is.
我是說正常
In the best way.
我姐姐不是怪物
And my sister's not a monster.
她差點殺死我
She nearly killed me.
-你自己滑倒在冰上的  -她變出的冰
- You slipped on ice... - Her ice!
那是意外  她嚇壞了
It was an accident. She was scared.
她不是故意的  她不是有意做這些的
She didn't mean it. She didn't mean any of this...
今晚的事是我的責任  是我逼的她
Tonight was my fault. I pushed her.
-所以該由我去把她找回來  -什麼
- So I'm the one that needs to go after her. - What?
-沒錯  -把我的馬牽過來
- Yeah. - Bring me my horse, please.
安娜  這太危險了
Anna, no. It's too dangerous.
艾爾莎不危險
Elsa's not dangerous.
我會把她找回來  讓這裡恢復正常
I'll bring her back, And I'll make this right.
-我跟你一起去  -不要
- I'm coming with you...- No.
我需要你留下幫我照看阿倫黛爾
I need you here to take care of Arendelle.
願盡綿薄之力
On my honor.
我委託漢斯王子管理這裡
I leave Prince Hans in charge!
你確定能信任她嗎
Are you sure you can trust her?
我不希望你受到傷害
I don't want you getting hurt.
她是我姐姐
She's my sister,
她絕不會傷害我的
She would never hurt me.
皚皚白雪覆蓋今夜的山
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight
埋藏身後我的足跡
Not a footprint to be seen
在這孤獨白色國度
A kingdom of isolation
我就是那冰雪的女王
And it looks like I'm the Queen
狂風呼號  內心亦湧動不能平息
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
不管多努力  再無法藏匿
Couldn't keep it in, Heaven knows I tried
掩藏好自己  不許人靠近
Don't let them in, Don't let them see
乖乖聽話  別讓大家擔心
Be the good girl you always have to be
把真心封閉  不讓人看清
Conceal, Don't feel, Don't let them know
如今被看清
Well, Now they know
不再躲  不再怕
Let it go. Let it go
秘密已經大白於天下
Can't hold it back anymore
不管他  不害怕
Let it go. Let it go
告別過去不留一絲牽掛
Turn away and slam the door
別人的話  何必在乎它
I don't care what they're going to say
就讓狂風怒號
Let the storm rage on
冰封千里我也從不害怕
The cold never bothered me anyway
現在回首遙望從前  往事變得微不足道
It's funny how some distance makes everything seem small
曾經桎梏我的恐懼
And the fears that once controlled me
也都遠的看不到
Can't get to me at all
展現自己  拿出本領
It's time to see what I can do
衝破極限  讓自己也吃驚
To test the limits and break through
沒有羈絆  扔掉規矩
No right, No wrong, No rules for me
世界由我
I'm free!
放寬心  向前進
Let it go! Let it go!
乘著風  融化在天際
I am one with the wind and sky
向前沖  不後悔
Let it go! Let it go!
我再沒有眼淚
You'll never see me cry
站在這裡
Here I stand and
堅定不移
Here I'll stay
任那狂風怒號
Let the storm rage on
雪花漫天飄下  這是我的魔法
My power flurries through the air into the ground
冰片旋轉紛飛  是我的靈魂在昇華
My soul is spiraling in frozen fractals all around
思緒結晶成冰淩  是冰雪的爆炸
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
過去已是過去
I'm never going back
是再也回不去
The past is in the past
不沉溺  不在意
Let it go! Let it go!
如晨曦一般冉冉升起
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
算了吧  忘了吧
Let it go! Let it go!
別指望我回到過去
That perfect girl is gone
站在這裡  不再藏匿
Here I stand in the light of day
任那狂風怒號
Let the storm rage on!
冰封千里我也從不害怕
The cold never bothered me anyway
艾爾莎  艾爾莎
Elsa! Elsa!
艾爾莎  是我安娜
Elsa, It's me, Anna...
老妹我不是故意讓你冰封夏天的
Your sister who didn't mean to make you freeze the summer.
對不起  都是我的錯
I'm sorry. It's all my f-f-fault.
當然  如果她對我坦誠點
Of course, none of this would have happened
也不會發生這樣的事兒
if she'd just told me her secret... ha...
她這個傢伙
She's a stinker.
不不不不  回來  不要跑
Oh no. No. No. No. Come back. No.
好吧
Oooo-Kay.
雪  幹嘛一定是雪
Snow, it had to be snow,
她就不能擁有熱帶魔法
She couldn't have had tr-tr-tropical magic
變出細細白沙和暖暖的...
that covered the f-f-fjords in white sand and warm...
火
Fire!
旅人歐肯的交易站
Wandering Oaken's Trading Post.
還有桑拿
And Sauna...
夏季大促銷
Big summer blow out.
游泳衣半價  木拖鞋
Half off swimming suits, clogs,
還有自產的防曬霜  怎麼樣
And a sun balm of my own invention, yah?
真不錯
Oh, great.
眼下而言  有靴子賣嗎
For now, how about boots,
有冬靴和衣服嗎
Winter boots... and dresses?
那些在冬季用品區
That would be in our winter department.
打聽一下  有沒有別的年輕女子
Oh. Um, I was just wondering, has another young woman,
比如女王之類的路過這裡
The Queen perhaps, I don't know, passed through here?
這種暴雪天氣只有你這麼神經會跑出來  親
Only one crazy enough to be out in this storm is you, dear.
還有這個傢伙
You and this fellow... Hoo hoo.
夏季大促銷
Big summer blow out.
-胡蘿蔔  -什麼
- Carrots. - Hah?
在你身後
Behind you.
哦  對不起
Oh, right. Excuse me.
真是七月飄雪啊
A real howler in July, yes?
這是從哪裡來的冷空氣
Where ever could it be coming from?
北山那邊
The North Mountain.
北山
North Mountain.
一共40塊
That'll be forty.
40塊  不行  10塊成交
Forty? No, ten.
不行呦  親
Oh dear, that's no good. See.
這是冬季庫存商品
These are from our winter stock,
現在供應量和需求量極度不平衡
where supply and demand have a big problem.
你跟我說供求的問題
You want to talk about a supply and demand problem?
我以賣冰塊為生
I sell ice for a living.
那現在你的生意可夠難做的
Ooh, that's a rough business to be in right now.
我是說  真是...
I mean, that is really...
真是不走運
Ahem. That's unfortunate.
40塊不能少  但可以贈送你
Still forty. But I will throw in a
一次歐肯獨家桑拿浴
visit to Oaken's sauna.
嗨  親愛的們
Hi, family.
我只有10塊  通融一下
Ten's all I got. Help me out.
那胡蘿蔔賣給你  不能再便宜了
Ten will get you this and no more.
我就問一件事
Okay, just tell me one thing...
北山那邊到底發生了什麼
What was happening on the North Mountain?
看起來像魔法嗎
Did it seem magical?
是的  麻煩讓開
Yes! Now, back up
讓我收拾這個奸商
while I deal with this crook here.
你叫我什麼
What did you call me?
好吧  好吧  疼
Okay. Okay, I'm-Ow! Whoa!
回見了您勒
Bye bye.
斯溫  我沒買到你的胡蘿蔔
No Sven, I didn't get your carrots.
但我找到了過夜的地方
But I did find us a place to sleep.
還是免費的
And it's free.
很抱歉剛才的暴力行為
I'm sorry about this violence.
我另送你一瓶醃鱈魚
I will add a quart of lutefisk,
彌補剛才的不愉快
so we'll have good feelings.
只要外套和靴子嗎
Just the outfit and boots, yah?
馴鹿比人類善良
Reindeers are better than people
斯溫  你說是不是
Sven, don't you think that's true
沒錯  人類會揍你  罵你  騙你
Yeah, people will beat you and curse you and cheat you
除了你  其他人很壞
Every one of em's bad, except you
謝謝你  老兄
Oh, Thanks, buddy.
但人類比馴鹿更好聞
But people smell better than reindeers
斯溫  你說對不對
Sven, don't you think I'm right
說得沒錯  但你可不香
That's once again true, for all Except you
被你說中了  讓我們休息吧
You got me, let's call it a night
晚安
Good night
小心不要被凍壞
Don't let the frostbite bite
不錯的二重唱
Nice duet.
是你啊
Oh, it's just you.
你想怎麼樣
What do you want?
我想讓你帶我去北山
I want you to take me up the North Mountain.
我不做嚮導的
I don't take people places.
我重說一遍吧
Let me rephrase that...
帶我去北山
Take me up the North Mountain...
拜託你
Please.
我知道如何停止寒冬
Look, I know how to stop this winter.
我們明早出發
We leave at dawn...
而且你忘了斯溫的胡蘿蔔
And you forgot the carrots for Sven.
抱歉  抱歉  我不是故意的
Oops. Sorry. Sorry. I'm sorry. I didn't...
我們現在就走  馬上走
We leave now. Right now.
抓牢  我們要加速了
Hang on! We like to go fast!
我喜歡加速
I like fast!
喂喂  放下你的腳  剛刷的漆
Whoa, whoa! Get your feet down. This is fresh lacquer.
說真的  你是鄉下長大的嗎
Seriously, were you raised in a barn?
不  我在城堡裡長大的
Ew. No, I was raised in a castle.
跟我說說  女王發了什麼瘋要冰封一切
So tell me, what made the Queen go all ice-crazy?
這個嘛  都是我的錯
Oh well, it was all my fault.
我訂了婚  她很不高興
I got engaged but then she freaked out because...
因為那個人是我那天剛認識的
I'd only just met him, you know, that day.
她說  她不會祝福我們的婚姻
And she said she wouldn't bless the marriage...
等等  你跟一個剛認識的人訂婚
Wait. You got engaged to someone you just met?
是  反正我生氣了  她也生氣了
Yeah. Anyway, I got mad and so she got mad.
她打算離開
And then she tried to walk away,
我一把抓下了她的手套
and I grabbed her glove...
等等  你是認真的嗎
Hang on. You mean to tell me.
你跟一個剛認識的人訂了婚
You got engaged to someone you just met?!
是的  專心聽  但事實上
Yes. Pay attention. But the thing is...
她一直帶著手套
she wore the gloves all the time,
我一直以為她只是有潔癖
So I just thought, maybe she has a thing about dirt.
你父母沒告訴過你小心陌生人嗎
Didn't your parents ever warn you about strangers?
他們說過
Yes, they did...
但漢斯不是陌生人
But Hans is not a stranger.
是嗎  他姓什麼
Oh yeah? What's his last name?
姓南部群島吧
...Of-the-Southern-Isles?
-他最喜歡吃是什麼  -三明治
- What's his favorite food? - Sandwiches.
-最好的朋友是誰  -可能叫約翰吧
- Best friend's name? - Probably John.
-眼睛的顏色  -夢幻般的顏色
- Eye color... - Dreamy.
-穿多大碼的鞋  -鞋碼很重要嗎
- Foot size? - Foot size doesn't matter.
你跟他一起吃過飯嗎
Have you had a meal with him yet?
如果你討厭他吃飯的樣子呢
What if you hate the way he eats?
如果你討厭他挖鼻屎呢
What if you hate the way he picks his nose?
挖鼻屎
Picks his nose?
然後吃掉
And eats it.
拜託  閣下  他是王子
Excuse me, sir. He's a Prince.
所有男人都這麼幹
All men do it.
這都不重要  我們是真愛
Ew. Look it doesn't matter, it's true love.
聽起來不像真愛
Doesn't sound like true love.
難道你是傳說中的愛情專家嗎
Are you some sort of love expert?
不是  但我朋友是
No. But I have friends who are.
你有朋友是愛情專家
You have friends who are love experts?
-我不信  -別說話
- I'm not buying it... - Stop talking.
不  不  我很樂意見見...
No, no, no. I'd like to meet these...
別說話  不是開玩笑
No, I mean it.
噓
Shhh.
斯溫  快跑  快跑
Sven, go. Go!
-那是什麼  -狼
- What are they? - Wolves.
狼
Wolves?
-我們該怎麼辦  -我來對付它們
- What do we do? - I've got this.
你坐好別掉下去  確保自己別被吃掉
You just... don't fall off and don't get eaten.
-但我想幫忙  -不行
- But I wanna help... - No.
為什麼不行
Why not?
因為我不相信你的判斷力
Because I don't trust your judgment.
你說什麼
Excuse me?!
誰會嫁給一個剛認識的陌生人
Who marries a man she just met?
我們是真愛
It's true love!
克裡斯托佛
Christopher!
是克裡斯托夫
It's Kristoff!
低頭
Duck!
-你差點把我點著  -但我沒有
- You almost set me on fire! - But I didn't.
準備跳  斯溫
Get ready to jump, Sven!
不需要你指揮它
You don't tell him what to do!
我說的算  跳  斯溫
I do! Jump, Sven!
我才還清貸款
But I just paid it off.
不  不  不  不
Uh-oh. No, no, no.
抓住
Grab on!
拉  斯溫  使勁拉
Pull, Sven! Pull!
我會賠償你的雪橇和所有損失
I'll replace your sled and everything in it.
如果你不想幫忙了  我完全理解
And I understand if you don't want to help me anymore.
我當然不想再幫她了
Of course I don't want to help her anymore.
這事兒讓我再也不想
In fact, this whole thing has ruined me
幫助任何人了
for helping anyone ever again.
-她自己會死掉的  -死就死吧
- But she'll die on her own. - I can live with that.
但如果她死了  就沒人賠你雪橇了
But you won't get your new sled if she's dead.
有時候你還真討厭
You know sometimes I really don't like you.
等等  我們來了
Hold up. We're coming.
真的嗎
You are?!
我是說  我可以讓你跟著
I mean, sure. I'll let you tag along.
-阿倫黛爾  -完全被冰雪覆蓋了
- Arendelle... - It's completely frozen.
沒有關係  艾爾莎會解凍一切的
But it'll be fine. Elsa will thaw it.
-她會嗎  -當然
- Will she? - Yeah.
我們走吧  北山是往這邊走嗎
Now come on. This way to the North Mountain?
準確的說是往那邊走
More like this way.
我從不知道冬天能如此美麗
I never knew winter could be so beautiful.
是的  真的很美  是不是
Yeah... It really is beautiful, isn't it?
但太潔白了
But it's so white.
弄點顏色如何
You know, how about a little color?
我覺得深紅色  黃綠色不錯
I'm thinking like maybe some crimson, chartreuse...
黃色如何  不行  不要黃色
How 'bout yellow...no, not yellow.
黃色  白雪  太不搭了
Yellow and snow? Brrrr... no go.
我說的對嗎
Am I right?
-你好  -你有點恐怖
- Hi! - You're creepy.
-我才不要  -別扔給我
- I don't want it! - Backatchya!
請別把我掉到地上  拜託  只是個腦袋
Please don't drop me. Come on, it's just a head.
不要給我
No!
看來這個初次見面不算美好
All right, we got off to a bad start.
他的身子
Ew, ew, the body!
等等  我眼前這些是什麼
Wait, what am I looking at right now?
為什麼你們跟蝙蝠一樣倒掛著
Why are you hanging off the earth like a bat?
好吧  等一下
...Al'right. Wait one second.
-謝謝你  -不客氣
- Oooh! Thank you! - You're welcome.
現在我帥呆了
Now I'm perfect.
差不多了
Well, almost.
好像整個世界都顛倒了
It was like my whole life got upside down.
太用力了  抱歉  我只是...
Oh! Too hard. I'm sorry! I was just...
-頭暈  -你沒事兒吧
- Woo! Head Rush! - Are you okay?
開什麼玩笑  我感覺好極了
Are you kidding me? I am wonderful!
我一直想要個鼻子
I've always wanted a nose.
太可愛了  就像小小的獨角獸
So cute. It's like a little baby unicorn.
怎麼啦
What? Hey! Whoa.
這樣更棒了
Oh, I love it even more! Hah...
讓我們重新認識一下
All right, let's start this thing over.
各位好  我叫奧洛夫  來個熱情的擁抱吧
Hi everyone. I'm Olaf. And I like warm hugs.
奧洛夫
Olaf?
是的  奧洛夫
That's right, Olaf.
小姐芳名啊
And you are?
我叫安娜
Oh, um... I'm Anna.
這頭滑稽的蠢驢是誰
And who's the funky-looking donkey over there?
它叫斯溫
That's Sven.
那這只馴鹿呢
Uh-huh. And who's the reindeer?
斯溫
Sven.
同名啊  真好記
They're...oh, okay...Makes things easier for me.
瞧瞧它  想親我的鼻子
Ha. Aw, look at him tryin' to kiss my nose.
我也喜歡你
I like you, too!
奧洛夫  你是艾爾莎造出來的嗎
Olaf, did Elsa build you?
是的  怎麼了
Yeah. Why?
-你知道她在哪嗎  -知道  怎麼了
- You know where she is? - Yeah. Why?
你能給我們引路嗎
Do you think you could show us the way?
-可以  怎麼了  -這是怎麼弄的
- Yeah. Why? - How does this work?
別鬧了  斯溫  談正事呢
Stop it, Sven. Trying to focus here.
-是的  怎麼了  -我告訴怎麼了
- Yeah, Why? - I'll tell you Why.
我們需要艾爾莎喚回夏天
We need Elsa to bring back Summer.
夏天啊
Summer?
我也不知道為什麼
Oh, I don't know why but.
但是我一直都很嚮往夏天
I've always loved the idea of summer,
還有太陽和所有一切炙熱的東西
and sun, and all things hot.
真的嗎
Really?
我猜你是沒怎麼接觸過高溫吧
I'm guessing you don't have much experience with heat.
沒有
Nope!
但是有時候我喜歡閉上眼睛
But sometimes I like to close my eyes
想像夏天真實來臨時的景象
and imagine what it'd be like when summer does come.
蜜蜂在蜂鳴  孩童吹起蒲公英的絨毛
Bees'll buzz, kids'll blow dandelion fuzz
而我就像個雪人一樣享受夏天
And I'll be doing whatever snow does in summer
手裡抓著杯飲料  躺在灼人的沙灘上
A drink in my hand, my snow up against the burning sand
也許還能曬個美麗的小麥色
Prob'ly getting gorgeously tanned in summer
我終於可以見證夏日的微風
I'll finally see a summer breeze
吹走冬日的暴風
Blow away a winter storm
我還要看看天氣變暖後
And find out what happens to
冰凍成塊的水會如何變化
Solid water, when it gets warm
我等不及想知道  我的小夥伴們都會怎麼看我
And I can't wait to see, what my buddies all think of me
想像一下我要是在夏天得有多酷呀
Just imagine how much cooler I'll be in summer
寒冷和炎熱都是如此的猛烈
The hot and the cold are both so intense
兩者結合  將會多麼轟烈
Put 'em together, it just makes sense
冬天適合待在室內相互依偎
Winter's a good time to stay in and cuddle
但是到了夏天  我將會成為一個
But put me in summer and I'll be a
幸福的雪人
Happy snowman
在生活艱辛之時  我喜歡堅持我的夢想
When life gets rough I like to hold on to my dream
想像自己在夏日裡慵懶地散發熱氣
Of relaxing in the summer sun just letting off steam
天空將會如此湛藍
Oh the sky will be blue
你們倆也會陪伴在我身邊
And you guys'll be there too
而我終將成為一個活在夏天的雪人
When I finally do what frozen things do in summer
-我要告訴他實情  -你敢
- I'm gonna tell him. - Don't you dare.
在炎夏
In summer
走吧  要找艾爾莎請跟我來
So, Come on! Elsa's this way.
咱們去把夏天捎回來吧
Let's go bring back summer!
我來了
I'm coming!
總得有人告訴他實情啊
Somebody's got to tell him.
不  不  你把有樹皮的那面朝下了
No. No. You've got the bark facing down.
樹皮那面要朝上放
The bark needs to be face-up.
樹皮朝下放更乾燥
Bark down is drier.
-樹皮朝上  -樹皮朝下
- Bark up... - Bark down.
斗篷  有人要斗篷嗎
Cloak. Does anyone need a cloak?
阿倫黛爾的人民感謝您  殿下
Arendelle is indebted to you, Your Highness.
城堡現在開放了  大廳裡有
The castle is open. There's soup
熱湯和格拉格熱飲[瑞典]
and hot glogg in the Great Hall.
給  把這些發下去
Here. Pass these out.
漢斯王子  我們是不是
Prince Hans, are we just
就得這麼坐在一旁
expected to sit here and freeze
瑟瑟發抖地看著你把阿倫黛爾的貨物免費發放完啊
while you give away all of Arendelle's tradable goods?
安娜公主已經下令
Princess Anna has given her orders and...
那是另一回事
And that's another thing,
你有沒有想過  你的公主
has it dawned on you that your Princess
可能正和邪惡的女巫密謀
may be conspiring with a wicked sorceress...
把全國人民都毀掉呢
to destroy us all?
不許質疑公主  她既然讓我掌權
Do not question the Princess. She left me in charge,
那我將毫不遲疑地
and I will not hesitate to
保護阿倫黛爾不受叛亂之苦
protect Arendelle from treason.
叛亂
Treason?!
夥計  冷靜  冷靜
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa, boy. Easy. Easy.
這是安娜公主的馬  她出什麼事了  她人呢
Princess Anna's horse. What happened to her? Where is she?
安娜公主身陷險境
Princess Anna is in trouble.
我需要志願者跟我一起找她
I need volunteers to go with me to find her!
我的侍從跟隨您  殿下
I volunteer two men, my Lord!
做好萬全準備
Be prepared for anything,
萬一你們遇見皇后
and should you encounter the Queen,
你們有權結束這個冬天
you are to put an end to this winter.
明白嗎
Do you understand?
你到底準備怎麼結束這個鬼天氣呢
So how exactly are you planning to stop this weather?
我準備跟我姐姐談談
Oh, I am gonna talk to my sister.
這就是你的計畫嗎  我的冰塊生意
That's your plan? My ice business is
就指著你跟你姐姐談談嗎
riding on you talking to your sister.
沒錯
Yup.
這麼說你是一點都不怕她咯
So you're not at all afraid of her?
-我為什麼要怕她呀  -就是說
- Why would I be? - Yeah.
我敢打賭艾爾莎一定是有史以來
I bet Elsa's the nicest, gentlest,
最善良最溫柔最溫暖的人了
warmest person ever.
看啊
Oh, look at that.
我被釘住了
I've been impaled.
現在怎麼辦
What now?
這懸崖太陡了  我只有一條繩子
It's too steep. I've only got one rope,
而你又不會爬山
and you don't know how to climb mountains.
誰說我不會
Says who?
你在幹嗎
What are you doing?
我要去見我姐姐
I'm going to see my sister.
你這是自殺的節奏呀  是我就不會踩那裡
You're going to kill yourself. I wouldn't put my foot there.
-你別讓我分心  -踩那也不行
- You're distracting me... - Or there.
你怎麼知道艾爾莎會肯見你呢
How do you know Elsa even wants to see you?
我要遮罩你
I'm just blocking you out 'cause
因為我得專心爬山
I gotta concentrate here.
你要知道大多數躲到深山裡的人
You know, most people who disappear
都是希望自己一個人待著的
into the mountains want to be alone.
沒人想要自己一個人待著  也許只有你
Nobody wants to be alone. Except maybe you.
我可不是獨自一人  我有朋友的  記得嗎
I'm not alone... I have friends, remember?
你是說那些愛情專家們
You mean the love experts?
沒錯  愛情專家們
Yes, the love experts!
我差不多爬到山頂了吧
Please tell me I'm almost there.
這裡的空氣是不是更稀薄了
Does the air seem a bit thin to you up here?
-堅持住  斯溫
- Hang on. - Hey, Sven?
我不知道我這算不算是解決了一大難題  但是
Not sure if this is going to solve the problem, but I found
我找到了一個臺階  正好通往你們的目的地
a staircase that leads exactly where you want it to go.
謝天謝地  接住我
Ha ha. Thank goodness. Catch!
謝謝了  我還怕你不接呢
Thanks! That was like a crazy trust exercise.
這麼多的冰  我快感動哭了
Now that's ice. I might cry.
哭吧  我不笑你
Go ahead. I won't judge.
好吧  慢慢來夥計  來  我扶著你
All right, take it easy boy. Come here, I gotcha.
好吧  你就在這等著  兄弟
Okay. You stay right here, buddy.
完美無瑕
Flawless.
敲門  敲門呀
Knock... just knock...
她怎麼還不敲門
Why isn't she knocking?
你說她是不是不會敲門啊
Do you think she knows how to knock?
門開了  這可是史無前例
It opened. That's a first.
你最好還是在外面等一下吧
You should probably wait out here.
什麼
What?
我上次向她引薦男人  她把一切都凍住了
Last time I introduced her to a guy, she froze everything.
可是  可是  拜託  這可是冰城啊
But. But... oh come on, It's a palace made of ice.
-冰就是我的生命啊  -拜拜  斯溫
- Ice is my life. - Bye, Sven.
你也在外面等  奧洛夫
You too, Olaf.
-我也要嗎  -讓我們倆單獨談談
- Me? - Just give us a minute.
好吧
Okay.
一  二  三  四
One... two... three... four...
艾爾莎  是我  安娜
Elsa? It's me... Anna.
安娜
Anna?
艾爾莎  你的樣子變了
Wow... Elsa, you look different...
變漂亮了  還有這個宮殿
It's a good different... and this place.
-真是美極了  -謝謝
- Is amazing. - Thank you.
我以前一直不知道自己的能力
I never knew what I was capable of.
對於之前發生的一切我很抱歉  要是我早知道...
I'm so sorry about what happened. If I'd known...
不  沒事的
No, it's okay.
你不需要道歉
You don't have to apologize.
但是也許你該走了  拜託
But you should probably go, please.
但是我才剛到呀
But I just got here.
阿倫黛爾才是你的歸屬
You belong in Arendelle.
-也是你的歸屬  -不  安娜  這裡才是
- So do you. - No, Anna. I belong here.
我一個人的
Alone.
我在這裡才能做真正的自己
Where I can be who I am,
不會傷害到任何人
without hurting anybody.
-實際上  關於這個問題  -58  59  60
- Actually, about that... - 58... 59... 60.
等一下  那是什麼聲音
Wait. What is that?
我叫奧洛夫  我喜歡熱情的擁抱
Hi, I'm Olaf and I like warm hugs.
奧洛夫
Olaf?
你堆出來的雪人  你還記得嗎
You built me. You remember that?
你居然活了
And you're alive?
我猜是吧
Um... I think so?
跟小時候堆的那個一模一樣
He's just like the one we built as kids.
咱們那時候多親啊
So we were so close.
我們可以再回到那個時候
We can be like that again.
慢點
Slow down.
安娜
Anna!
不  我們回不去了
No, We can't.
-再見  安娜  -艾爾莎  等等
- Goodbye, Anna. - Elsa, wait.
別過來  我是在保護你
No, I'm just trying to protect you.
你用不著保護我  我不害怕
You don't have to protect me. I'm not afraid.
求你別再把我拒之門外了
Please don't shut me out again.
求求你別再關上心門
Please don't slam the door.
你不需要再跟我保持距離
You don't have to keep your distance anymore
因為這麼久以來
'Cause for the first time in forever
我終於理解了你
I finally understand
好久以來第一次  我們可以攜手解決問題
For the first time in forever, we can fix this hand in hand
我們可以一同走下這座冰山
We can head down this mountain together
你無需再生活在恐懼中
You don't have to live in fear
好久以來我終於可以說
'Cause for the first time in forever
我會待在你身邊
I will be right here
安娜  求你回家去吧
Anna, please go back home
美好的生活等著你
Your life awaits.
去享受陽光  敞開大門
Go enjoy the sun and open up the gates
-可是  -我知道  你是一片好意
- Yeah, but... - I know! You mean well
但我心意已決
But leave me be.
是  我是獨自一人  但我可以享受自由
Yes, I'm alone. But I'm alone and free.
和我保持距離  你便不會受到傷害
Just stay away and you'll be safe from me
-實際上  這是不可能的  -什麼意思
- Actually, we're not - What do you mean you're not
看來你還不知道
I get the feeling you don't know
我不知道什麼
What do I not know
阿倫黛爾被很厚很厚很厚的積雪覆蓋
Arendelle's in deep deep deep deep snow
什麼
What?
你把所有地方都變成了冬天
You kind of set off an eternal winter... everywhere.
所有地方
Everywhere?
沒事的  你解凍一下就好了
It's okay, you can just unfreeze it.
不行
No, I can't.
-我不知道怎麼解凍  -你肯定會的
- I don't know how. - Sure you can.
我知道你會
I know you can!
因為好久以來
'Cause for the first time in forever
我真是個傻瓜  我無法擁有自由
I'm such a fool! I can't be free
你無需再恐懼
You don't have to be afraid
永遠無法逃離我內心的暴風雪
No escape from the storm inside of me
我們可以一同解決
We can work this out together
我無法掌控我身上的詛咒
I can't control the curse
我們能逆轉嚴冬
We'll reverse the storm you've made
安娜  拜託  你只會越弄越糟
Anna, please, You'll only make it worse
別驚慌
Don't panic
我內心充滿了恐懼
There's so much fear
我們會讓陽光再度普照
We'll make the sun shine bright
你在這不安全
You're not safe here
我們可以共同面對
We can face this thing together
我做不到
I can't
安娜  你沒事吧
Anna. Are you okay?
-我沒事  我挺好的  -這是誰
- I'm okay. I'm fine. - Who's this?
等一下  這都不重要了  你們走吧
Wait, it doesn't matter. Just... you have to go.
不  我知道我們能找到辦法
No, I know we can figure this out together.
什麼辦法  你有什麼能力來結束這寒冬
How? What power do you have to stop this winter?
來阻止我
To stop me?
安娜  我們該走了
Anna, I think we should go.
不  你不走我也不走  艾爾莎
No. I'm not leaving without you, Elsa.
你必須走
Yes, you are.
住手  放我們下來
Stop. Put us down!
走開
Go away!
小心
Heads up!
小心我的屁股
Watch out for my butt!
把人拋來拋去的很不禮貌耶
It is not nice to throw people!
小辣椒  別生氣了
Wow, wow, wow feisty pants. Ok, relax.
冷靜點  冷靜點
Just calm down. Calm down.
好吧  我沒事了
All Right. I'm Okay.
別理那個雪人就是了
Just let the snow man be.
-我很冷靜  -很好
- I'm calm. - Great.
拜託
Come on!
你看  這下好了  你把它惹急了
See. Now you made him mad!
我去引開他
I'll distract him.
你們倆趕緊跑
You guys go.
不  不  我不是說你們
No, no, not you guys.
這下麻煩了
This just got a whole lot harder.
你在幹嘛
What are you doing?
我打到他了
I got him!
這得有三十多米吧
It's a hundred foot drop.
是六十多米
It's two hundred.
-你這是要幹嗎  -我在挖雪錨
- What's that for? - I'm digging a snow anchor.
好吧  要是我們摔下去怎麼辦
Okay. What if we fall?
下面的積雪有大概六米
There's twenty feet of fresh powder down there.
摔下去也會感覺像是掉在了枕頭上
It'll be like landing on a pillow...
至少我希望如此
hopefully.
好了  安娜  數到三
Okay, Anna. On three.
-一  -好吧  要跳的時候告訴我
- One... - Okay. You tell me when...
-二  -我準備好了  我時刻準備著  沒錯
- Two... - I'm ready to go... I was born ready! Yes!
冷靜點
Calm down.
樹
Tree!
搞什麼...  好吧  這事也常有
What the... Whoa! That happened.
天啊  我身材還真是超級走樣啊
Ah. Ah. Man, am I out of shape.
好了  安娜  斯溫
There we go. Hey, Anna! Sven!
你們倆跑哪去了  我們把那個大個子甩得遠遠的了
Where'd ya guys go? We totally lost marshmallow back there!
我們正說到你呢
Hey. We were just talking about you.
都是好話  都是好話
All good things, all good things.
不
No!
這樣也沒什麼分別  對吧
This is not making much of a difference! Is it?
奧洛夫
Olaf!
-堅持住  夥計們  -爬快點
- Hang in there, guys! - Go faster!
等一下  搞什麼
Wait, what?
克裡斯托夫
Kristoff!
別再回來了
Don't come back!
我們不會再來了
We won't.
你說的沒錯耶  真的像掉在枕頭上一樣
Hey, you were right. Just like a pillow.
奧洛夫
Olaf!
我的腿沒有知覺了
I can't feel my legs!
那是我的腿
Those are my legs.
幫個忙  抓住我的屁股
Hey, do me a favor, grab my butt.
感覺好多了
Oh, that feels better.
斯溫  他找到咱們了
Hey, Sven! He found us.
這只可愛的小馴鹿
Who's my cute little reindeer?
不許這麼跟他講話
Don't talk to him like that.
來
Here.
-你沒事吧  -謝謝
- You okay? - Thank you.
你的頭沒事吧
Um... how's your head?
沒事  我挺好的
I mean, It's fine. Ah... I'm good.
我腦殼比較厚
Ha. I've got a thick skull.
我就沒有腦殼  也沒有骨頭
I don't have a skull... or bones.
那麼
So...
-現在怎麼辦  -現在怎麼辦
- So now what? - Now what?
現在怎麼辦
Now what?!
我該怎麼辦呢
Oooh! What am I gonna do?
她把我趕出來了  我不能任由天氣這個樣子
She threw me out. I can't go back to
就逃回阿倫黛爾
Arendelle with the weather like this.
再說還有你的冰塊生意...
And then there's your ice business...
別擔心我的冰塊生意
Hey, hey, don't worry about my ice business.
-還是擔心一下你的頭髮吧  -什麼
- Worry about your hair. - What?
我剛從懸崖上掉下來  你的頭髮也很亂好嗎
Just fell off a cliff. You should see your hair.
不是  你的頭髮變白了
No, yours is turning white.
變白了  怎麼會  搞什麼
White? It's... what?
是因為她打到你了  對吧
It's because she struck you, isn't it?
看上去很糟嗎
Does it look bad?
-沒有  -你猶豫了
- No. - You hesitated.
不  我沒有  安娜  我們得找人幫忙  知道嗎  走吧
No, I didn't. Anna, you need help. Okay? Come on.
-好吧  我們這是去哪  -去找我的朋友們
- Okay! Where are we going? - To see my friends.
-那些愛情專家嗎  -愛情專家
- The love experts? - Love experts?!
別擔心  他們會治好你的
And don't worry, they'll be able to fix this.
你怎麼知道
How do you know?
因為我曾經看過他們治好你
Because I've seen them do it before.
我覺得我自己也是個愛情專家
I like to consider myself a love expert.
別慌  控制住
Get it together. Control it.
別去感受  別去感受
Don't feel. Don't feel.
別去感受
Don't feel!
看呀  斯溫  夜空還亮著
Look, Sven. The sky's awake.
-你冷嗎  -有點
- Are you cold? - A little.
等一下  過來
Wait. Come here.
關於我的朋友們
So, about my friends...
我說他們是朋友  其實他們更像是我的家人
Well, I say friends, they're more like family.
總之  在我小的時候  只有我和斯溫相依為命
Anyway, when I was a kid, it was just me and Sven
直到他們收留了我們
until you know, they took us in.
-真的嗎  -是啊
- They did? - Yeah.
我不想嚇唬你  但是他們
I don't want to scare you, they can be
有時候不太會說話
a little bit inappropriate.
而且嗓門很大  非常大
And loud... very loud...
他們有時還會很固執  還有點
They're also stubborn at times, and a little
專橫  並且很沉  非常非常沉  所以你...
overbearing. And heavy. Really, really heavy. Which you...
但是你別擔心  他們也還好  他們本意不壞
But you know, you're okay. They're fine. They mean well.
克裡斯托夫  他們聽起來很棒
Kristoff, they sound wonderful.
那好吧
Okay then.
這就是我的家人
Meet my family.
夥計們
Hey, guys!
他們都是石頭
They're rocks.
他是個瘋子
He's crazy.
我差點認不出你來了  怎麼重了這麼多
Hey, Wow... I pretty recognize you, What's so much weigh?
我來引開他們的注意力  你趕緊逃
I'll distract them while you run.
斯溫的家人們  見到你們很高興
Hi, Sven's family! It's nice to meet you!
安娜  因為我很愛你  所以你趕緊逃
Anna, because I love you, I insist you run.
我聽說你們是愛情專家
I understand you're love experts!
你怎麼還不逃
Why aren't you running?
好吧  我要去...
Okay. Um... I'm gonna go...
不  不  不  安娜  等一下
No, no, no. Anna, wait!
克裡斯托夫
Kristoff!
克裡斯托夫回來了
Kristoff's home!
克裡斯托夫  克裡斯托夫回來了  你走了好久啊
Kristoff! Kristoff's home! It's been too long!
克裡斯托夫回來了
Kristoff's home!
等一下  克裡斯托夫
Wait? Kristoff?
讓我好好看看你
Yeah... Oh, let me look at you!
把衣服脫下來  克裡斯托夫  我來給你洗洗
Oh, take off your clothes, Kristoff, I wash them.
不  我還是穿著衣服吧
Ah! No. I'm gonna keep my clothes on. Look.
見到你們很高興
it's great to see you all.
-但是老帕比呢  -他在午睡
- But where's Grand Pabbie? - He's napping.
可是你看  我長出蘑菇來了
But look, I grew a mushroom.
我贏得了一塊火晶
And I earned my fire crystal.
我取了一塊腎結石
I passed a kidney stone.
克裡斯托夫  抱我起來
Kristoff, pick me up.
你長大了  不錯啊
You're getting big! Good for you.
地精  它們是地精啊
Trolls? They're trolls.
他還帶回來個姑娘
He's brought a girl!
她就像個小蛋糕
She's like a little cupcake.
什麼情況
What's going on?
我早就習慣它們了
I've learned to just roll with it.
我看看
Let me see.
眼睛明亮  鼻子好使  牙齒堅固
Bright eyes. Working nose. Strong teeth.
好好好  她跟我們家克裡斯托夫很般配
Yes, yes, yes. She'll do nicely for our Kristoff.
等等  不是的
Wait. Oh, no.
你們誤會了
You've got the wrong idea.
她不是我女朋友
That's not why I brought her here.
對  我們不是  我不是...
Right. We're not. I'm not...
問題出在哪兒啊  親愛的
What's the issue, dear?
你為何拒絕他呢
Why are you holding back from such a man?
因為他走路很笨拙
Is it the clumpy way he walks
什麼
What?
還是他講話太粗魯
Or the grumpy way he talks
不是
No.
還是他的腳丫太奇怪
Or the pear-shaped, square-shaped
四四又方方  大鴨梨一樣
weirdness of his feet
行了吧
Hey!
他雖然勤洗澡
And though we know he washes well
可還是有味道
he always ends up sorta smelly
但他細心又可愛  世間絕無雙
But you'll never meet a fella who's as sensitive and sweet
很好啊  但是...
That's nice, but...
他也許不完美
So he's a bit of a fixer upper
也有些缺點
So he's got a few flaws
他思維很奇葩
His peculiar brain, dear
又為馴鹿癡狂
His thing for the reindeer
這有些不合常理
That outside a few of nature's laws
我才不是這樣的
This is not about me!
他還需要改良
So he's a bit of a fixer upper
但是我們堅信
But this we're certain of
你只要給他一點愛
You can fix this fixer upper up
就會讓他發光
with a little bit of love
我們能不能先別說這個了
Can we just stop talking about this?!
我們真遇上了麻煩
We've got a real, actual problem here.
親愛的告訴我
I'll say...so tell me dear.
是因為他容易膽怯
Is it the way that he runs scared
還是他不善社交
Or that he's socially impaired
還是他只愛伐木  在森林中央
Or that he only likes to tinkle in the woods
我不需要知道這個
I do not need to know that.
因為金髮太娘炮
Are you holding back your fondness
所以你不喜歡他
Due to his unmanly blondeness
還是他假裝不靠譜
Or the way he covers up
把自己隱藏
that he's the honest goods
他只是不完美
He's just a bit of a fixer upper
他有些小瑕疵
He's got a couple a' bugs
我才沒有
No, I don't.
別看他不善交往
His isolation is confirmation of
正說明他渴望擁抱
his desperation for healing hugs
他有些不完美
So he's a bit of a fixer upper
但我們有辦法
But we know what to do
我們的辦法就是讓
The way to fix up this fixer upper
你來雕琢他
is to fix him up with you
停停停  你們夠了
Stop it. Stop it. Stop it. Enough!
她都和別人訂婚了好嗎
She's engaged to someone else. Okay?!
所以問題出在她
So she's a bit of a fixer upper
這更不重要
That's a minor thing
口頭訂婚能取消
This quote engagement is a flex arrangement
也沒戒指在她手上
And by the way, I don't see no ring
所以問題出在她
So she's a bit of a fixer upper
她在猶豫彷徨
Her brain's a bit betwixt
別讓未婚夫擋道
Get the fiance out of the way
一切就會如常
and the whole thing will be fixed
我們不是說讓你改變他
We aren't saying you can change him
因為改變一個人很難
'Cause people don't really change
我們只是想說  愛是一種力量
We're only saying that love's a force
強大而奇妙
That's powerful and strange
因為瘋狂擔心  焦慮恐慌
People make bad choices
人們才會失誤
if they're mad or scared or stressed
但是給他們一點愛
But throw a little love their way
給他們一點愛
throw a little love their way
你就能讓他們做到最好
And you'll bring out their best
真愛讓人做到最好
True love brings out the best
每個人都不完美
Everyone's a bit of a fixer upper
人生就是這樣
That's what it's all about
父親母親  姐妹兄弟
Father, sister, brother
我們都相互需要
We need each other
幫我們變好  讓我們成長
to raise us up and round us out
每個人都不完美
Everyone's a bit of a fixer upper
但到緊要關頭
But when push comes to shove
能讓你我變完美的
The only fixer upper fixer that can fix a fixer upper is
就是真真真真愛
True, True, True, True, Love
真愛至上
Love, Love, Love, True Love
至上
True-e-e-e-e-e
安娜
Do you, Anna,
你願意讓克裡斯托夫做你腫誠的...
take Kristoff to be your trollfully wedded...
等等  什麼
Wait, what?!
你要結婚啦
You're getting married.
安娜
Anna!
她冷得像冰一樣
She's as cold as ice.
她被施了奇怪的魔法
There's strange magic here!
老帕比
Grand Pabbie!
來來  讓我看看
Come, come. Bring her to me.
安娜  你有生命危險
Anna, your life is in danger.
你的心被你姐姐冰凍了
There is ice in your heart, put there by your sister.
如果不解除魔咒
If not removed,
冰會一點點加厚  最後把你永遠冰封
to solid ice will you freeze, forever.
什麼  不會吧
What? No.
你能除掉寒冰的  對吧
But you can remove it, right?
抱歉  克裡斯托夫  我不能
I can not, I'm sorry Kristoff.
如果是頭部還好
If it was her head that would be easy,
但如果心被冰凍
but only an act of true love
只有真愛才能融化
can thaw a frozen heart.
真愛
An act of true love?
也許是真愛之吻
A true love's kiss, perhaps?
安娜  我們得帶你回漢斯那兒
Anna, we've got to get you back to Hans.
漢斯
Hans.
我們走  斯溫
Pull us out, Sven.
-奧洛夫  快走  -我來了
- Olaf! Come on. - I'm coming!
我們去吻漢斯  漢斯是誰啊
Let's go kiss Hans! Who is this Hans?!
我們是來找安娜公主的
We are here to find Princess Anna.
大家要提高警惕
Be on guard,
但不能傷害女王
but no harm is to come to the Queen.
-明白了嗎  -明白  殿下
- Do you understand? - Yes, Sir.
女王
The Queen.
快  快
Go, go!
快點
Get on!
在上面  快
Up there! Come on!
她跑不掉了
We got her.
別  求你們了
No, please.
別過來
Stay away!
射箭  射箭
Fire! Fire!
抓住她  抓住她
Get her! Get her!
艾爾莎女王
Queen Elsa!
別變成可怕的惡魔
Don't be the monster they fear you are.
不  我...我幹了什麼
No. What... what have I done?
你為什麼把我帶到這兒
Why did you bring me here?
我不能眼睜睜看著他們殺了你
I couldn't just let them kill you.
但我會危及阿倫黛爾
But I'm a danger to Arendelle.
去找安娜
Get Anna.
安娜還沒回來
Anna has not returned.
請你結束冬天
If you would just stop the winter,
帶回夏天  拜託了
bring back summer. Please.
你還不明白嗎  我做不到
Don't you see? I can't.
你必須讓他們放了我
You have to tell them to let me go.
我儘量吧
I will do what I can.
堅持住  夥計  快點
Just hang in there. Come on, buddy, faster!
我們城堡見吧
I'll meet you guys at the castle!
別被人發現  奧洛夫
Stay out of sight, Olaf!
不會的
I will!
是安娜公主
It's Princess Anna!
你沒...沒事吧
Are you g... gonna be okay?
別擔心我
Don't worry about me.
安娜  我們擔心死你了
Anna! Oh, you had us worried sick...
殿下
My Lady.
給她取暖  快去找漢斯王子
Get her warm and find Prince Hans, immediately.
我們會的  謝謝你了
We will. Thank you.
一定要保證她安全
Make sure she's safe!
我要回去找安娜公主
I'm going back out to look for Princess Anna.
你不能再冒這個險了
You cannot risk going out there again.
如果她有個三長兩短...
If anything happens to her...
如果公主殿下遭遇不測
If anything happens to the Princess,
阿倫黛爾可就指望您了
you are all Arendelle has left.
他在這兒  漢斯王子
He's in here. Prince Hans.
安娜  你身上好冷
Anna. You're so cold.
-漢斯  你必須吻我  -什麼
- Hans, you have to kiss me. - What?
現在
Now.
-馬上  -冷靜點
- Now.  - Settle down.
我們讓你倆單獨待會兒
We'll give you two some privacy.
發生了什麼
What happened out there?
艾爾莎用魔法襲擊了我
Elsa struck me with her powers.
你說她不會傷害你的
You said she'd never hurt you.
我想錯了
I was wrong.
安娜
Anna?
她冰凍了我的心
She froze my heart
只有真愛才能救我的命
and only an act of true love can save me.
真愛之吻
A true love's kiss.
安娜啊
Oh, Anna...
要是真有人愛你就好了
If only there was someone out there who loved you.
什麼
What?
你說你愛我的
You said you did.
作為我們王國的第十三名王子
As thirteenth in line in my own kingdom,
我是沒機會掌權的
I didn't stand a chance.
我知道...
I knew...
我必須去和其他王室聯姻
I'd have to marry into the throne somewhere.
你在說些什麼
What are you talking about?
作為繼承人  當然艾爾莎更好
As heir, Elsa was preferable, of course.
但是沒人能接近她
But no one was getting anywhere with her.
-而你呢...  -漢斯
- But you... - Hans?
你那麼渴望愛
You were so desperate for love.
你很願意嫁給我  就這樣
You were willing to marry me, just like that.
我都想好了  娶了你之後呢
I figured, after we married,
我就讓艾爾莎出點小意外
I'd have to stage a little accident for Elsa.
漢斯  別這樣
Hans. No, stop.
誰知道她把自己毀了
But then she doomed herself,
你還蠢到家了去找她
and you were dumb enough to go after her.
別這樣
Please.
現在只需要殺掉艾爾莎
All that's left now is to kill Elsa
讓夏天回來嘍
and bring back summer.
你根本比不上艾爾莎
You're no match for Elsa.
不  是你比不上艾爾莎
No, you're no match for Elsa.
我呢  從另一方面說  現在可是英雄
I, on the other hand, am the hero
我將把阿倫黛爾從毀滅的危險中解救出來
who is going to save Arendelle from destruction.
你不會得逞的
You won't get away with this.
可我已經得逞嘍
Oh, I already have.
來人啊  救命
Please, somebody help.
救救我  救救我
Please, please!
天越來越冷了
It's getting colder by the minute.
如果不趕緊採取措施
If we don't do something soon,
都會被凍死的
we'll all freeze to death.
-漢斯王子  -安娜公主已經...
- Prince Hans. - Princess Anna is...
-不在了  -什麼
- dead. - What...?
她怎麼了
What happened to her?
她被艾爾莎女王殺掉了
She was killed by Queen Elsa.
那可是她親姐姐啊
Her own sister.
幸好在她死在我懷中之前
At least we got to say our marriage vows
我們結婚了
before she died in my arms.
現在毋庸置疑了
There can be no doubt now.
艾爾莎女王是個怪物
Queen Elsa is a monster
我們都有危險
and we are all in grave danger.
漢斯殿下  阿倫黛爾就靠您了
Prince Hans, Arendelle looks to you.
我沉重宣佈
With a heavy heart,
阿倫黛爾的艾爾莎女王犯叛國罪
I charge Queen Elsa of Arendelle with treason
我判處她死刑
and sentence her to death.
快點
Hurry up!
她很危險  動作要快  不能疏忽
She's dangerous. Move quickly and be careful.
-門打不開  -凍住了
- The door's not open! - It's frozen.
幹嘛啊  夥計  我說  當心點
What is it, buddy? Hey, watch it.
你這是怎麼了
What's wrong with you?
你這麼說我聽不明白
I don't understand you when you talk like that.
停下  放我下來
Ah! Stop it! Put me down!
別這樣  斯溫  我們不會回去的
No, Sven! We're not going back!
人家和她真愛在一起呢
She's with her true love.
這是什麼...
What the...
安娜
Anna!
快點  快點啊哥們
Come on! Come on, boy!
救命
Help.
安娜  不是吧
Anna. Oh no.
奧洛夫  奧洛夫  離那兒遠點
Olaf? Olaf. Get away from there.
這就是熱的感覺啊  我喜歡
So this is heat. I love it.
但我可不能碰
Ooh! But don't touch it!
漢斯哪去了  你的吻呢
So, where's Hans? What happened to your kiss?
我看走眼了  他不是真愛
I was wrong about him. It wasn't true love.
我們白跑了那麼遠的路回來
But we ran all the way here?
奧洛夫  你不能待在這兒
Please Olaf, you can't stay here,
會融化的
you'll melt.
在找到真愛救你之前
I am not leaving here
我不會離開你的
until we find some other act of true love to save you.
你有什麼主意嗎
Do you happen to have any ideas?
我都不明白什麼是愛
I don't even know what love is.
那沒關係  我明白
That's okay, I do.
愛就是...
Love is...
把某個人看得比自己還重
putting someone else's needs before yours,
比如
like, you know,
克裡斯托夫把你送回漢斯身邊
how Kristoff brought you back here to Hans
然後永遠離開
and left you forever.
克裡斯托夫愛我嗎
Kristoff loves me?
你是真的不懂愛啊
Wow, you really don't know anything about love, do you?
奧洛夫  你要融化了
Olaf, you're melting.
為了某些人粉身碎骨都值得
Some people are worth melting for.
但現在好像不是時候
Just maybe not right this second.
別擔心  我去搞定
Don't worry, I've got it!
我們得想個辦法...
We're going to get through...
等等  我看見什麼了
Oh, wait. Hang on. I'm getting something.
是克裡斯托夫和斯溫
It's Kristoff and Sven!
他們回來了
They're coming back this way.
是他們
They... they are?
他跑得真快啊
Wow, he's really moving fast.
我可能想錯了
I guess I was wrong.
克裡斯托夫還沒愛你愛到完全放下你
I guess Kristoff doesn't love you enough to leave you behind.
扶我起來  奧洛夫  拜託
Help me up, Olaf. Please.
不不不
No, no, no, no, no.
你得待在爐火邊取暖
You need to stay by the fire and keep warm.
-我得去找克裡斯托夫  -幹嘛
- I need to get to Kristoff. - Why?
我知道為什麼了
Oh, oh, oh, I know why.
他是你的真愛啊
There's your act of true love right there,
就是那個勇士一般穿越峽灣
riding across the fjords like a valiant,
體味刺鼻的馴鹿國王
pungent reindeer King!
快走吧
Come on!
小心
Look out!
走這邊
Back this way!
我們被困住了
We're trapped.
安娜  滑下去
Slide, Anna.
成功了
We made it!
走走走
Go, Go, Go, Go...
快點啊  夥計  快點
Come on, buddy, faster.
克裡斯托夫
Kristoff!
不要停
Keep going!
克裡斯托夫
Kristoff!
不要...
No...
斯溫
Sven!
好樣的
Good boy.
克裡斯托夫
Kristoff.
安娜
Anna!
艾爾莎
Elsa.
你不能一走了之
You can't run from this!
-照顧好我妹妹  -你妹妹
- Just take care of my sister. - Your sister?
她從山裡回來了  冰冷虛弱
She returned from the mountain weak and cold.
她說你冰凍了她的心
She said you froze her heart.
我努力救她  但還是來不及了
I tried to save her, but it was too late.
她的皮膚結了冰  頭髮也變白了
Her skin was ice. Her hair turned white.
你妹妹死了  都是你幹的
Your sister is dead... because of you.
不
No!
克裡斯托夫
Kristoff?
安娜
Anna!
艾爾莎
Elsa?
不
No!
安娜
Anna!
安娜  不要啊  求你了
Oh, Anna... no... no, please no.
安娜
Anna.
Anna?
安娜
艾爾莎
Oh, Elsa.
你犧牲了自己來救我
You sacrificed yourself for me?
我愛你啊
I love you.
真愛能融化冰凍的心
An act of true love will thaw a frozen heart.
真愛會融化...
Love will thaw...
對啊  是愛
Love. Of course.
- 艾爾莎  -原來是愛啊
- Elsa? - Love.
我就知道你可以的
I knew you could do it.
毫無疑問  這是我今生最棒的一天
Hands down, this is the best day of my life
也很可能是最後一天
and quite possibly the last.
奧洛夫  挺住啊  小傢伙
Oh, Olaf. Hang on, little guy.
我自己的冰雪雲哎
Hey, my own personal flurry.
安娜   她不是冰凍了你的心嗎
Anna? But she froze your heart.
這裡你的心最冷
The only frozen heart around here is yours.
幹的漂亮
Fantastic!
我會把這個惡棍遣送回國的
I will return this scoundrel to his country.
我們可以看看
We shall see
他的十二個哥哥怎麼處理他
what his twelve big brothers think of his behavior.
阿倫黛爾感謝您  殿下
Arendelle thanks you, my Lord.
這不合理
This is unacceptable.
我是無辜的  我也受到了驚嚇
I am innocent. I'm a victim of fear.
我受到了創傷  我的脖子疼
I've been traumatized. Ow! My neck hurts.
我能否看下醫生  算了
Is there a doctor I could see? No.
我要見女王
I demand to see the Queen!
我這兒有女王的聖旨
I have a message from the Queen.
從今往後
Arendelle will henceforth and forever
阿倫黛爾永不與猥瑣屯進行任何貿易往來
no longer do business of any sort with Weaseltown.
韋瑟頓  是韋瑟頓
Weselton. It's Weselton!
快來快來快來
Come on. Come on. Come on. Come on!
好好好  我來了
Ow, Okay, Okay, here I come.
-柱子...  -抱歉
- Pole... - Oops. So Sorry.
好了好了  到了
Okay. Okay. Here we are.
我欠你的雪橇
I owe you a sled.
你沒開玩笑吧
Are you serious?
當然沒有  而且這是最新款的
Yes. And it's the latest model.
不行  我不能要
No. I can't accept this.
你必須要  不退不換  女王的命令
You have to. No returns. No exchanges. Queen's orders.
你是阿倫黛爾官方制定冰塊供應商
She's named you the official Arendelle Ice Master and Deliverer.
-什麼  這不行吧  -當然行
- What? That's not a thing. - Sure it is.
而且還有個獎盃  你喜歡嗎
And it even has a cup holder. Do you like it?
喜歡  簡直是愛死了
Like it? I love it!
我真想吻你
I could kiss you!
我可以 我意思是我想我...
I could. I mean I'd like to. I'd...
我可以嗎  我...你...
May I? We me...
我是說  我們可以嗎
I mean, may we?
等等  什麼
Wait, what?
我們可以的
We may.
夏天
Summer!
你們好
Hello.
大家準備好了嗎
Are you ready?
門開著真好
I like the open gates.
我們再也不會關門了
We are never closing them again.
艾爾莎  這是很漂亮
Oh, Elsa, they're beautiful,
但我不會滑...
but you know I don't ska...
來吧  你可以的
Come on, you can do it!
當心  馴鹿過去了
Look out! The reindeer is coming through!
我站不穩  站不穩
I don't got it. I don't got it!
我來啦
Hey, guys!
奧洛夫
Olaf!